<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="church_page_1">
        ## CONNECT\n\n

        * What is the first thing that comes to mind when you think of church?\n
        * What were your first/early experiences of attending church?\n
        * Were those positive or negative experiences in your faith journey and why?\n\n

        ## STUDY\n\n

        > *Simon Peter replied, \“You are the Christ, the son of the living God.\” And Jesus answered him, \“blessed are you, Simon bar Jonah for
flesh and blood has not revealed this to you, but my father who is in heaven. And I tell you, you are Peter, and on this rock, I will build my church, and the gates of hell shall not prevail against it (Matthew 16:16-18)*\n\n

        Through a revelation of the Holy Spirit, Peter confessed the true identity of Jesus, the Son of the living God. Jesus said this truth would be the foundation stone that his church would be built on. He also described the type of church he would build a victorious church that would overcome the Kingdom of darkness. Jesus and Paul used the word church in reference to the people of God. The church was never referred to as a religious building.\n\n

        Following are four benefits of being part of a local church.
    </string>

    <string name="church_page_2_part_1">
        ## Friendship\n\n

        Real friends. Everyone needs them. Few find them.\n\n

        > *A friend loves at all times, and a brother is born of **adversity**. (Proverbs 17:17)*\n\n
        > *A man of many companions will come to ruin, but there is a friend who sticks closer than a brother (Proverbs 18:24)*
    </string>

    <string name="church_page_2_part_2">
        The best place to look for a real friend is in the church, the people of God. True friends are those who have our best interests in mind. They stick with us through thick and thin. Real friends never lead us away from God. Instead, they provoke us to godliness.\n\n

        ## Fellowship\n\n

        2. How does the fellowship of the church help you stay red- hot for the Lord?\n
        > *And they devoted themselves to the apostles’ teaching and the **fellowship**, to the breaking of bread and the prayers. And all who believed were together and had all things in common. And they were selling their possessions and belongings and distributing the proceeds to all, as any had need. And day by day, attending the temple together and breaking bread in their homes, they receive their food with gladness and generous hearts (Acts 2:42, 44-46)*\n\n

        > *Do not be unequally yoked with unbelievers for what partnership has righteousness with lawlessness? Or **what fellowship has light with darkness**? (II Corinthians 6:14)*
    </string>

    <string name="church_page_2_part_3">
        If a piece of burning coal is removed from the fire, it will cool off. If it is put back in the middle of a pile of red-hot coals, it will burn again. The same is true with Christians. If a Christian is removed from fellowship with other red-hot Christians, he will cool off spiritually. **If a Christian stays in fellowship, he will stay on fire for God**.
    </string>

    <string name="church_page_3_part_1">
        ## Worship\n\n

        God is looking for sincere worshippers. Worship is simply the expression of our love, devotion, and commitment to God.\n\n

        3. Why is worshipping in the church important?\n
        > *But the hours coming, and is now here, when the true worshippers will worship the father in spirit and truth, for the father is seeking such people to worship him. God is spirit, and those who worship him must worship in spirit and truth (John 4:23-24)*
    </string>

    <string name="church_page_3_part_2">
        God didn’t call us to gather and worship to burden us but to bless us. Church attendance can become one of the greatest blessings in your and your family’s life!\n\n

        ## Discipleship\n\n

        4. From the verses below what does it mean to be a disciple?\n
        > *Go therefore and **make disciples** of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit, teaching them **to observe all that I have commanded** you. And behold, I am with you always, to the end of the age (Matthew 28:19-20)*\n\n

        > *And what you have heard from me in the presence of many witnesses entrust to faithful men who will be able to teach others also (2 Timothy 2:2)*
    </string>

    <string name="church_page_3_part_3">
        The last command Jesus gave his followers before he ascended to heaven was to go and make disciples, baptize these disciples, and teach them how to obey God’s word. Therefore, we should first be disciples or followers of Jesus, then we should teach others to follow him.\n\n

        In church, we have the opportunity to be discipled and to make disciples.\n\n

        ## Personal Application\n\n

        * Are you being discipled, either one-to-one or in a small group setting?\n
        * Are you making disciples? Who are you teaching to obey God’s Word?\n
        * Are you an active member of a local church?\n
        * Name three Christians you can call for help in case of a spiritual emergency.\n\n

        ## MEMORY VERSE\n\n

        > *And all who believed were together and had all things in common. And they were selling their possessions and belongings and distributing the proceeds to all, as any had need. (Acts 2:44-45)*
    </string>
</resources>