<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <!-- getting started strings -->
    <string name="getting_started_page_1">
        *“And Jesus said to them, follow me, and I will make you become fishers of men.” (Mark 1:17)*\n\n

        These five steps will get you off to the right start, as you follow Christ.\n\n

        1. **Stop trusting yourself and your good works and start trusting in Christ alone for Salvation**. *“And by grace you have been saved through faith. And this is not your own doing, it is the gift of God, not a result of works, Tso that no one may boast.” (Ephesians 2:8-9)*\n
        2. **Turn away from everything the Bible calls sin**. *“But God’s firm foundation stands, bearing this steel, the Lord knows those are who are his and let everyone who names the name of the Lord depart from iniquity.” (2 Timothy 2:19)*\n
        3. **Attend a small group for personal discipleship and weekly worship service**. *And let us consider how to stir up one another to love and good works, not neglecting to meet together, as is the habit of some, but encouraging one another, and all the more as you see the day drawing near”. (Hebrews 10: 24-25)*\n
        4. **Read and obey your Bible every day**. *This Book of the Law shall not depart from your mouth, but you shall meditate on it day and night, so that you may be careful to do according to all that is written in it. For then you will make your way prosperous, and then you will have good success. (Joshua 1:8)*\n
        5. **Tell others about your new relationship with Christ**. *“And he did not permit him but said to him, go home to your friends and tell them how much the Lord has done for you, and how he has had mercy on you. And he went away and began to proclaim in the Decapolis how much Jesus had done for him, and everyone marveled” (Mark 5:19-20)*
    </string>
    <string name="getting_started_page_2">
        In every physical structure, the foundation is important. A building that has no strong foundation inevitably collapses. Likewise, a Christian that has no strong spiritual foundation is also in danger of spiritual collapse. Jesus reminds us of its importance at the end of the Sermon on the Mount.\n\n

        *…Everyone then who hears these words of mine and does them will be like a wise man **who built his house on the rock**. And the rain fell, and the floods came, and the winds blew and beat on that house, but it did not fall, because it had been founded on the rock. And everyone who hears these words of mine and does not do them will be like a foolish man who **built his house on the sand**. And the rain fell, and the floods came, and the winds blew and beat against that house, and it fell, and great was the fall of it. (Matthew 7:24-27)*\n\n

        In this parable, Jesus gives two kinds of foundation. One is the rock foundation; the other is the sand foundation. One can build his life on the rock by knowing and obeying the Word. Or one can build his life on the sand by simply ignoring it.\n
        I believe that you want to start this journey because you want to build your life on the rock. And that rock is the Lord Jesus Christ. He is our foundation.
    </string>
    <string name="getting_started_page_3">
        How the Lessons Are Structured\n\n

        * CONNECT – Understand that discipleship isn’t just finishing the material. It’s about building a relationship.\n
        * STUDY – Discipleship is built on the Word of God, not on the opinion of man. Learn how to read and study the Bible and discover God’s answer to our every spiritual need.\n
        * APPLY – Discipleship is about obedience. It’s not about how much you know but how much you obey.\n\n

        We are excited about how God will use this journey to help you grow in your relationship with Jesus.
    </string>

    <!-- salvation strings -->
    <string name="salvation_page_1">
        ## CONNECT\n

        * What comes into your mind when you think of the word salvation?\n
        * In your own opinion, why do you think we need to be saved? Or do we need to be saved?\n

        ## STUDY\n

        *Therefore, if anyone is **in Christ**, he is a **new creation**. The old has passed away; behold, **the new has come**. (2 Corinthians 5:17 ESV)*\n
        In its simplest sense, being a Christian means being a **new creation**. It means a fresh start. That’s good news for all of us. However, before we can appreciate the good news, we need to understand why we need to start over. Why do we need to become a new creation? Why do we need salvation?\n
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_2_part_1">
        ## The Problem\n

        1. There is an immeasurable gap separating God and man. What is the cause of this eternal separation? (Read Isaiah 59:1-2)\n
        *Behold, the Lord’s hand is not shortened, that it cannot save, or his ear dull, that it cannot hear; but your iniquities have made a separation between you and your God, and your sins have hidden his face from you so that he does not hear. (Isaiah 59:1-2)*\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_2_part_2">
        Have you ever felt distant from God? We all have. Feeling far from God is very common. Many who sense the vast separation suppose that if they meditate harder, learn more about their religion, or just step into a religious sanctuary, they will be closer to God. But our separation from God is not just physical or intellectual so neither meditation nor knowledge or religious ritual can bring us any closer to God.\n\n
        2. How does the Bible describe this separation?\n
        *…for all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God… (Romans 3:23)*
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_3_part_1">
        The separation between God and man is **moral separation**. God is holy, man is not. God is good, man is not. God\'s standard is his glory, meaning his perfections. The problem is that we cannot be morally perfect like God. That’s why all are **eternally separated** from God. In other words, we are **disqualified** on our own to go to heaven.\n\n
        3. Furthermore, we need to understand that **sin has consequences**. What is the eternal consequence of our sin ac- cording to Romans 6:23?\n
        *For the wages of sin is **death**… (Romans 6:23)*
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_3_part_2">
        The consequence of our sin is eternal death. Eternal separation from God in a place called Hell.\n

        \n\n**The Solution**\n\n

        The Good News is that God did not leave us on our own to deal with our sins. God’s justice demands that **sin must be punished**. That’s why Jesus came to sacrifice Himself and paid the penalty for our sin on the cross.\n\n
        **God is holy**, righteous, and just, that’s why he could not allow sin to go unpunished. But **God is loving** and compassionate and merciful, he did not want man to be eternally separated from him. How can God punish our sins without eternally condemning us from His presence?\n\n
        The divine solution to this problem was for Jesus, God’s only son, to become the sacrifice for our sin.\n
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_4_part_1">
        4. How did Jesus’ deal with our sin according to Hebrews 9:26-28?\n
        *…for then he would have had to suffer repeatedly since the foundation of the world. But as it is, he has **appeared once** for all at the end of the ages **to put away sin by the sacrifice of himself**. And just as it is appointed for man to die once, and after that comes judgment, so Christ, **having been offered once to bear the sins of many**, will appear a second time, not to deal with sin but to save those who are eagerly waiting for him. (Hebrews 9:26-28)*\n
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_4_part_2">
        What exactly happened on the cross? Through his death on the cross, **Jesus took our place and our punishment**. He **exchanged** his righteousness for our sin. He took our curse and gave us His blessing. Because of his sinless life, Jesus was the only one qualified to pay the penalty for man’s sin and to bridge the gap between God and man.\n\n
        5. What did God do for us in Jesus according to 2 Corinthians 5:21?\n
        *For our sake he made him **to be sin** who knew no sin, so that in him **we might become the righteousness of God**. (2 Corinthians 5:21)
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_5_part_1">
        6. What did Christ redeem us **from** in Galatians 3:13?\n
        *Christ redeemed us **from the curse of the law** by becoming a curse for us——for it is written, “Cursed is everyone who is hanged on a tree” (Galatians 3:13)*\n
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_5_part_2">
        **The Result**\n\n

        Christ died on the cross so that we might receive **forgiveness** of our sins, be **reconciled** to God, have **eternal life**, and **be indwelt by the Spirit**.\n*Forgiveness*\n\n
        7. In Ephesians 1:7, what did we receive in Jesus?\n
        *In him, we have **redemption** through his blood, the **forgiveness of our trespasses**, according to the riches of his grace… (Ephesians 1:7)*
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_5_part_3">
        8. How many sins did God forgive us in Jesus? (1 John 1:7)\n
        *…the blood of Jesus his Son cleanses us from all sin. (1 John 1:7)*\n
        God forgives us and cleanses us from all of our sins. All means our past, present, and future sins. Our status before God in Christ is forgiven.
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_6_part_1">
        *Reconciliation*\n\n

        Our sins make us the enemy of God. But the good news of the Gospel is that God in Christ offers us reconciliation to God.\n\n

        9. What did Romans 5:10 say about our past and present status before God?\n
        *For if while we were **enemies** we were **reconciled** to God by the death of his Son, much more, now that we are reconciled, shall we be saved by his life. (Romans 5:10)*
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_6_part_2">
        To be reconciled with God means God is no longer your enemy. You have been brought near to God through Jesus as a friend.\n\n

        *Eternal Life*\n\n

        Not only does God forgives us and reconciles us through Jesus, but He also gives us eternal life.\n
        *“For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have *eternal life*. (John 3:16)*\n\n

        10. What is eternal life according to John 17:3?\n
        *And this is eternal life, that **they know you the only true God**, and Jesus Christ whom you have sent. (John 17:3)*
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_7">
        Eternal life does not primarily refer to quantity but the quality of life. It is a life of knowing God and Jesus. It is a life lived with God.\n\n

        *Indwelt by the Spirit*\n\n

        One of the blessings of being a Christian is to be indwelt by God’s Spirit.\n

        *If the Spirit of him who raised Jesus from the dead dwells in you, he who raised Christ Jesus from the dead will also give life to your mortal bodies through his Spirit who dwells in you. (Romans 8:11)*\n\n

        When you accept Christ as your Savior, the Holy Spirit takes up **residence** in your heart, bringing with Him an entirely new life of love, relationship, and service to the Lord.\n\n

        This is what it means to be a new creation.To have a fresh start.\n\n

        ## The Response\n\n

        How do we receive this salvation? We receive salvation when we **stop trusting in ourselves** and **start trusting in who Christ is and what He has done for us**.
        Our salvation is the result of **God’s grace**. It is based on what Jesus did for us on the cross. It has nothing to do with what we do for him. We cannot save ourselves or earn God’s approval through the good works we do.\n\n

        11. Can we earn our salvation through good works? Read Ephesians 2:8-9.\n
        *For by grace, you have been saved through faith. And **this is not your own doing; it is the gift of God**, not a result of works, so that no one may boast. (Ephesians 2:8-9)*
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_8_part_1">
        12. According to the verse above, how do you receive this gift?
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_8_part_2">
        What is saving faith?\n\n

        * Saving faith means you **understand intellectually**. You need to know that you are a sinner and therefore unworthy to go to heaven. You also need to understand the purpose and the reason why Jesus died on the cross for you.\n
        * Saving faith means you **agree emotionally**. Not only do you understand it, but you heartily agree with it. You are struck emotionally by how much God loves you on the cross of Jesus Christ.\n
        * Saving faith means you **trust volitionally**. It means you totally depend on Jesus’ work on the cross alone for your salvation.\n\n

        13. What does it look like to express this kind of saving faith? (Read Romans 10:9-10)\n
        *…if you **confess** with your mouth that Jesus is Lord and **believe in your heart** that God raised him from the dead, you will be saved. (Romans 10:9)*
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_9">
        ## PERSONAL APPLICATION\n\n

        * Have you stopped trusting in yourself and started trust- ing in Christ alone for salvation?\n
        * Have you turned away from all known sin?\n
        * Have you confessed Jesus as the Lord and Master of your life?\n
        * Are you willing to follow and obey Him for the rest of your life?\n\n

        ## PRAY\n\n

        ### Prayer for Salvation\n\n

        Heavenly Father, I acknowledged the separation between us… It is because of my sins. I confess that I have sinned and have fallen short of your glory. Thank you that you sent your Son, Jesus to pay the penalty for my sin. I believe that He died on the cross for me. I believe that you raised him from the dead. I am sorry for my sins, and I ask you to forgive and cleanse me.\nI want to turn away from everything the Bible calls sin and receive Jesus as my Lord, Master, and Savior. Help me to love, serve and obey you for the rest of my life in Jesus’ name, Amen.
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_10">
        ## A New Life\n\n

        If you have sincerely prayed that prayer, the Bible promises that the old has passed away and new has come. The next lessons will introduce you to some of the new things that have come.\n\n

        ## MEMORY VERSE\n\n

        *For by grace you have been saved through faith. And this is not your own doing; it is the gift of God, not a result of works, so that no one may boast. (Ephesians 2:8-9)*
    </string>

    <!-- lordship strings -->
    <string name="lordship_page_1">
        ## CONNECT\n\n

        * Tell us about one person who has greatly influenced you, and what difference they made in your life.\n
        * Recall a time when you had to make a big decision. What was your decision-making process, and did it involve others?\n\n

        ## STUDY\n\n

        *“Let all the House of Israel therefore know for certain that God has made him both Lord and Christ, this Jesus whom you crucified.” (Acts 2:36)*\n\n

        Lordship is one of the central messages of the Bible. Jesus is referred to as Lord 100 times in the book of Acts and 622 times in the whole New Testament,
        while being referred to as savior only twice in Acts and twenty-four times in the New Testament. The biblical emphasis is overwhelmingly on the concept of lordship. Lord means master, the one who calls the shots, the one who makes the decisions.
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_2_part_1">
        ## Lordship and Salvation\n\n

        1. What does Romans 10:9 teach us about believing and Lordship?\n
        *“If you confess with your mouth that Jesus is Lord and believe in your heart that God raised him from the dead, you will be saved.” (Romans 10:9)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_2_part_2">
        The starting point of the Christian life is the acknowledgment of the Lordship of Christ. Confessing Jesus as Lord implies a submission to his Lordship in every area of life. If Jesus is our savior, then we should make Him our Lord.\n
        The brilliant author C.S. Lewis pointed out, that Jesus is either Lord of all as He repeatedly claimed, or he is a lunatic or a liar. It would be foolish to trust Jesus to save you or to follow him if he is not Lord of all as he claimed. If I say, “Jesus is Lord,” that means he is my master in every area of my life. This declaration is more than intellectual assent or lip service. It means we submit ourselves fully to him.
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_3_part_1">
        ## Lordship demands Obedience\n\n

        2. From Luke 6:46 and Matthew 7:21, what did Jesus teach us about Lordship?\n
        *“Why do you call me Lord, Lord, and do not do what I tell you?” (Luke 6:46)*\n
        *“Not everyone who says to me, Lord, Lord, will enter the Kingdom of heaven, but **the one who does the will** of my father who is in heaven.” (Matthew 7:21)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_3_part_2">
        As disciples of Jesus, our lives must be characterized by growing obedience to his commands.\n\n

        3. According to Jesus what is the Great Commandment in the Bible we must obey?\n
        *“Teacher, which is the great commandment in the Law?” And he said to him, “**You shall love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind**. This is the great and first commandment. And a second is like it: **You shall love your neighbor as yourself**. On these two commandments depend all the Law and the Prophets.” (Matthew 22:36-40)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_3_part_3">
        4. According to John 14:15, what does real love for God look like?\n
        *“If you love me, you will **keep my commandments**. (John 14:15)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_4_part_1">
        5. What is God’s view of the person who goes through life pursuing wealth?\n
        *And he told them a parable, saying, “The land of a rich man produced plentifully, and he thought to himself, ‘What shall I do, for I have nowhere to store my crops?’ And he said, ‘I will do this: I will tear down my barns and build larger ones, and there I will store all my grain and my goods. And I will say to my soul, “Soul, you have ample goods laid up for many years; relax, eat, drink, be merry.”’ But God said to him, ‘Fool! This night your soul is required of you, and the things you have prepared, whose will they be?’ So is the one who lays up treasure for himself and is not rich toward God.” (Luke 12:16-21)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_4_part_2">
        There’s nothing wrong with wealth. What is wrong is when money and possession replace the role of God in our life. Jesus calls a person who trusts and pursues wealth more than the will of God a fool.\n\n

        6. Is it possible to serve God and the world or ourselves?\n
        *“**No one can serve two masters**, for either he will hate the one and love the other, or he will be devoted to the one and despise the other. **You cannot serve God and money**. (Matthew 6:24)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_5_part_1">
        7. Where should we store our treasure?\n
        *“Do not lay up for yourselves treasures on earth, where moth and rust destroy and where thieves break in and steal, but *lay up for yourselves treasures in heaven*, where neither moth nor rust destroys and where thieves do not break in and steal. For where your treasure is, there your heart will be also. (Matthew 6:19-21)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_5_part_2">
        8. What is the major difference between the things of the world and the things of God?\n
        *Do not love the world or the things in the world. If anyone loves the world, the love of the Father is not in him. For all that is in the world——the desires of the flesh and the desires of the eyes and pride of life——**is not from the Father** but is from the world. And **the world is passing away along with its desires**, but whoever does the will of God abides forever. (1 John 2:15-17)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_6_part_1">
        ## Lordship begins in the heart\n\n

        9. According to 1 Peter 3:5, where does honoring Christ as Lord begins?\n
        *“But *in your hearts* honor Christ the Lord as holy” (I Peter 3:5)*\n\n

        Submitting to Christ as Lord is not about following a set of religious rules and traditions. Rather, **lordship is a matter of the heart**. Lordship begins as an internal submission of the heart. If it is genuine, it will eventually manifest itself in obedience.\n\n

        10. Explain in your own words what Colossians 3:23-24 means:\n
        *Whatever you do, work heartily, as for the Lord and not for men, knowing that from the Lord you will receive the inheritance as your reward. You are serving the Lord Christ. (Colossians 3:23-24)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_6_part_2">
        ## Lordship is a Continuous Walk\n\n

        11. What is the evidence that Jesus is your Lord?\n
        *“Therefore, as you received Christ Jesus the Lord so walk in him” (Colossians 2:6)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_6_part_3">
        We begin our Christian walk by acknowledging that Jesus is Lord. We must continue to walk under his lordship for the rest of our lives. Lordship is not having a one-time experience with God, but developing a lifetime walk with God. The more we know Him, the more we submit to Him.\n\n

        12. What does Luke 9:23 says we must continually do as we walk under the Lordship of Christ day by day?\n
        *And he said to all, “If anyone would come after me, **let him deny himself and take up his cross daily** and follow me. (Luke 9:23)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_7_part_1">
        Following Jesus and making him Lord means denying myself daily. It means that when what I want conflicts with what God wants, I have denied what I want to do what God wants.\n\n

        What do you think this means practically in your life?
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_7_part_2">
        13. What promise do we have from God if we are willing to put Him first?\n
        *But seek first the kingdom of God and his righteousness, and **all these things will be added to you**. (Matthew 6:33)*\n
        *And **my God will supply every need** of yours according to his riches in glory in Christ Jesus. (Philippians 4:19)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_7_part_3">
        ## Personal Application\n\n

        * Are there areas in your life that you have not yet submitted to the Lordship of Jesus Christ? Areas you are struggling to obey God.\n
        * Are your relationships under his lordship?\n
        * Are your finances under his lordship?\n
        * Is your time submitted to his lordship?\n

        ## MEMORY VERSE\n\n

        *…if you confess with your mouth that Jesus is Lord and believe in your heart that God raised him from the dead, you will be saved. (Romans 10:9)*
    </string>
</resources>
