<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <!-- getting started strings -->
    <string name="getting_started_page_1">
        *“And Jesus said to them, follow me, and I will make you become fishers of men.” (Mark 1:17)*\n\n

        These five steps will get you off to the right start, as you follow Christ.\n\n

        1. **Stop trusting yourself and your good works and start trusting in Christ alone for Salvation**. *“And by grace you have been saved through faith. And this is not your own doing, it is the gift of God, not a result of works, Tso that no one may boast.” (Ephesians 2:8-9)*\n
        2. **Turn away from everything the Bible calls sin**. *“But God’s firm foundation stands, bearing this steel, the Lord knows those are who are his and let everyone who names the name of the Lord depart from iniquity.” (2 Timothy 2:19)*\n
        3. **Attend a small group for personal discipleship and weekly worship service**. *And let us consider how to stir up one another to love and good works, not neglecting to meet together, as is the habit of some, but encouraging one another, and all the more as you see the day drawing near”. (Hebrews 10: 24-25)*\n
        4. **Read and obey your Bible every day**. *This Book of the Law shall not depart from your mouth, but you shall meditate on it day and night, so that you may be careful to do according to all that is written in it. For then you will make your way prosperous, and then you will have good success. (Joshua 1:8)*\n
        5. **Tell others about your new relationship with Christ**. *“And he did not permit him but said to him, go home to your friends and tell them how much the Lord has done for you, and how he has had mercy on you. And he went away and began to proclaim in the Decapolis how much Jesus had done for him, and everyone marveled” (Mark 5:19-20)*
    </string>
    <string name="getting_started_page_2">
        In every physical structure, the foundation is important. A building that has no strong foundation inevitably collapses. Likewise, a Christian that has no strong spiritual foundation is also in danger of spiritual collapse. Jesus reminds us of its importance at the end of the Sermon on the Mount.\n\n

        > *…Everyone then who hears these words of mine and does them will be like a wise man **who built his house on the rock**. And the rain fell, and the floods came, and the winds blew and beat on that house, but it did not fall, because it had been founded on the rock. And everyone who hears these words of mine and does not do them will be like a foolish man who **built his house on the sand**. And the rain fell, and the floods came, and the winds blew and beat against that house, and it fell, and great was the fall of it. (Matthew 7:24-27)*\n\n

        In this parable, Jesus gives two kinds of foundation. One is the rock foundation; the other is the sand foundation. One can build his life on the rock by knowing and obeying the Word. Or one can build his life on the sand by simply ignoring it.\n
        I believe that you want to start this journey because you want to build your life on the rock. And that rock is the Lord Jesus Christ. He is our foundation.
    </string>
    <string name="getting_started_page_3">
        How the Lessons Are Structured\n\n

        * **CONNECT** – Understand that discipleship isn’t just finishing the material. It’s about building a relationship.\n
        * **STUDY** – Discipleship is built on the Word of God, not on the opinion of man. Learn how to read and study the Bible and discover God’s answer to our every spiritual need.\n
        * **APPLY** – Discipleship is about obedience. It’s not about how much you know but how much you obey.\n\n

        We are excited about how God will use this journey to help you grow in your relationship with Jesus.
    </string>

    <!-- salvation strings -->
    <string name="salvation_page_1">
        ## CONNECT\n

        * What comes into your mind when you think of the word salvation?\n
        * In your own opinion, why do you think we need to be saved? Or do we need to be saved?\n

        ## STUDY\n

        *Therefore, if anyone is **in Christ**, he is a **new creation**. The old has passed away; behold, **the new has come**. (2 Corinthians 5:17 ESV)*\n\n
        In its simplest sense, being a Christian means being a **new creation**. It means a fresh start. That’s good news for all of us. However, before we can appreciate the good news, we need to understand why we need to start over. Why do we need to become a new creation? Why do we need salvation?\n
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_2_part_1">
        ## The Problem\n

        1. There is an immeasurable gap separating God and man. What is the cause of this eternal separation? (Read Isaiah 59:1-2)\n\n
        *Behold, the Lord’s hand is not shortened, that it cannot save, or his ear dull, that it cannot hear; but your iniquities have made a separation between you and your God, and your sins have hidden his face from you so that he does not hear. (Isaiah 59:1-2)*\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_2_part_2">
        Have you ever felt distant from God? We all have. Feeling far from God is very common. Many who sense the vast separation suppose that if they meditate harder, learn more about their religion, or just step into a religious sanctuary, they will be closer to God. But our separation from God is not just physical or intellectual so neither meditation nor knowledge or religious ritual can bring us any closer to God.\n\n
        2. How does the Bible describe this separation?\n\n
        *…for all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God… (Romans 3:23)*
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_3_part_1">
        The separation between God and man is **moral separation**. God is holy, man is not. God is good, man is not. God\'s standard is his glory, meaning his perfections. The problem is that we cannot be morally perfect like God. That’s why all are **eternally separated** from God. In other words, we are **disqualified** on our own to go to heaven.\n\n
        3. Furthermore, we need to understand that **sin has consequences**. What is the eternal consequence of our sin ac- cording to Romans 6:23?\n\n
        *For the wages of sin is **death**… (Romans 6:23)*
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_3_part_2">
        The consequence of our sin is eternal death. Eternal separation from God in a place called Hell.\n

        \n\n**The Solution**\n\n

        The Good News is that God did not leave us on our own to deal with our sins. God’s justice demands that **sin must be punished**. That’s why Jesus came to sacrifice Himself and paid the penalty for our sin on the cross.\n\n
        **God is holy**, righteous, and just, that’s why he could not allow sin to go unpunished. But **God is loving** and compassionate and merciful, he did not want man to be eternally separated from him. How can God punish our sins without eternally condemning us from His presence?\n\n
        The divine solution to this problem was for Jesus, God’s only son, to become the sacrifice for our sin.\n
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_4_part_1">
        4. How did Jesus’ deal with our sin according to Hebrews 9:26-28?\n\n
        *…for then he would have had to suffer repeatedly since the foundation of the world. But as it is, he has **appeared once** for all at the end of the ages **to put away sin by the sacrifice of himself**. And just as it is appointed for man to die once, and after that comes judgment, so Christ, **having been offered once to bear the sins of many**, will appear a second time, not to deal with sin but to save those who are eagerly waiting for him. (Hebrews 9:26-28)*\n
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_4_part_2">
        What exactly happened on the cross? Through his death on the cross, **Jesus took our place and our punishment**. He **exchanged** his righteousness for our sin. He took our curse and gave us His blessing. Because of his sinless life, Jesus was the only one qualified to pay the penalty for man’s sin and to bridge the gap between God and man.\n\n
        5. What did God do for us in Jesus according to 2 Corinthians 5:21?\n\n
        *For our sake he made him **to be sin** who knew no sin, so that in him **we might become the righteousness of God**. (2 Corinthians 5:21)
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_5_part_1">
        6. What did Christ redeem us **from** in Galatians 3:13?\n
        *Christ redeemed us **from the curse of the law** by becoming a curse for us——for it is written, “Cursed is everyone who is hanged on a tree” (Galatians 3:13)*\n
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_5_part_2">
        **The Result**\n\n

        Christ died on the cross so that we might receive **forgiveness** of our sins, be **reconciled** to God, have **eternal life**, and **be indwelt by the Spirit**.\n*Forgiveness*\n\n
        7. In Ephesians 1:7, what did we receive in Jesus?\n\n
        *In him, we have **redemption** through his blood, the **forgiveness of our trespasses**, according to the riches of his grace… (Ephesians 1:7)*
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_5_part_3">
        8. How many sins did God forgive us in Jesus? (1 John 1:7)\n\n
        *…the blood of Jesus his Son cleanses us from all sin. (1 John 1:7)*\n\n
        God forgives us and cleanses us from all of our sins. All means our past, present, and future sins. Our status before God in Christ is forgiven.
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_6_part_1">
        *Reconciliation*\n\n

        Our sins make us the enemy of God. But the good news of the Gospel is that God in Christ offers us reconciliation to God.\n\n

        9. What did Romans 5:10 say about our past and present status before God?\n\n
        *For if while we were **enemies** we were **reconciled** to God by the death of his Son, much more, now that we are reconciled, shall we be saved by his life. (Romans 5:10)*
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_6_part_2">
        To be reconciled with God means God is no longer your enemy. You have been brought near to God through Jesus as a friend.\n\n

        *Eternal Life*\n\n

        Not only does God forgives us and reconciles us through Jesus, but He also gives us eternal life.\n\n
        *“For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have *eternal life*. (John 3:16)*\n\n

        10. What is eternal life according to John 17:3?\n\n
        *And this is eternal life, that **they know you the only true God**, and Jesus Christ whom you have sent. (John 17:3)*
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_7">
        Eternal life does not primarily refer to quantity but the quality of life. It is a life of knowing God and Jesus. It is a life lived with God.\n\n

        *Indwelt by the Spirit*\n\n

        One of the blessings of being a Christian is to be indwelt by God’s Spirit.\n\n

        *If the Spirit of him who raised Jesus from the dead dwells in you, he who raised Christ Jesus from the dead will also give life to your mortal bodies through his Spirit who dwells in you. (Romans 8:11)*\n\n

        When you accept Christ as your Savior, the Holy Spirit takes up **residence** in your heart, bringing with Him an entirely new life of love, relationship, and service to the Lord.\n\n

        This is what it means to be a new creation.To have a fresh start.\n\n

        ## The Response\n\n

        How do we receive this salvation? We receive salvation when we **stop trusting in ourselves** and **start trusting in who Christ is and what He has done for us**.
        Our salvation is the result of **God’s grace**. It is based on what Jesus did for us on the cross. It has nothing to do with what we do for him. We cannot save ourselves or earn God’s approval through the good works we do.\n\n

        11. Can we earn our salvation through good works? Read Ephesians 2:8-9.\n\n
        *For by grace, you have been saved through faith. And **this is not your own doing; it is the gift of God**, not a result of works, so that no one may boast. (Ephesians 2:8-9)*
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_8_part_1">
        12. According to the verse above, how do you receive this gift?
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_8_part_2">
        What is saving faith?\n\n

        * Saving faith means you **understand intellectually**. You need to know that you are a sinner and therefore unworthy to go to heaven. You also need to understand the purpose and the reason why Jesus died on the cross for you.\n
        * Saving faith means you **agree emotionally**. Not only do you understand it, but you heartily agree with it. You are struck emotionally by how much God loves you on the cross of Jesus Christ.\n
        * Saving faith means you **trust volitionally**. It means you totally depend on Jesus’ work on the cross alone for your salvation.\n\n

        13. What does it look like to express this kind of saving faith? (Read Romans 10:9-10)\n\n
        *…if you **confess** with your mouth that Jesus is Lord and **believe in your heart** that God raised him from the dead, you will be saved. (Romans 10:9)*
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_9">
        ## PERSONAL APPLICATION\n\n

        * Have you stopped trusting in yourself and started trusting in Christ alone for salvation?\n
        * Have you turned away from all known sin?\n
        * Have you confessed Jesus as the Lord and Master of your life?\n
        * Are you willing to follow and obey Him for the rest of your life?\n\n

        ## PRAY\n\n

        ### Prayer for Salvation\n\n

        Heavenly Father, I acknowledged the separation between us… It is because of my sins. I confess that I have sinned and have fallen short of your glory. Thank you that you sent your Son, Jesus to pay the penalty for my sin. I believe that He died on the cross for me. I believe that you raised him from the dead. I am sorry for my sins, and I ask you to forgive and cleanse me.
        I want to turn away from everything the Bible calls sin and receive Jesus as my Lord, Master, and Savior. Help me to love, serve and obey you for the rest of my life in Jesus’ name, Amen.
    </string>
    <string name="salvation_page_10">
        ## A New Life\n\n

        If you have sincerely prayed that prayer, the Bible promises that the old has passed away and new has come. The next lessons will introduce you to some of the new things that have come.\n\n

        ## MEMORY VERSE\n\n

        *For by grace you have been saved through faith. And this is not your own doing; it is the gift of God, not a result of works, so that no one may boast. (Ephesians 2:8-9)*
    </string>

    <!-- lordship strings -->
    <string name="lordship_page_1">
        ## CONNECT\n\n

        * Tell us about one person who has greatly influenced you, and what difference they made in your life.\n
        * Recall a time when you had to make a big decision. What was your decision-making process, and did it involve others?\n\n

        ## STUDY\n\n

        *“Let all the House of Israel therefore know for certain that God has made him both Lord and Christ, this Jesus whom you crucified.” (Acts 2:36)*\n\n

        Lordship is one of the central messages of the Bible. Jesus is referred to as Lord 100 times in the book of Acts and 622 times in the whole New Testament,
        while being referred to as savior only twice in Acts and twenty-four times in the New Testament. The biblical emphasis is overwhelmingly on the concept of lordship. Lord means master, the one who calls the shots, the one who makes the decisions.
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_2_part_1">
        ## Lordship and Salvation\n\n

        1. What does Romans 10:9 teach us about believing and Lordship?\n
        *“If you confess with your mouth that Jesus is Lord and believe in your heart that God raised him from the dead, you will be saved.” (Romans 10:9)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_2_part_2">
        The starting point of the Christian life is the acknowledgment of the Lordship of Christ. Confessing Jesus as Lord implies a submission to his Lordship in every area of life. If Jesus is our savior, then we should make Him our Lord.\n
        The brilliant author C.S. Lewis pointed out, that Jesus is either Lord of all as He repeatedly claimed, or he is a lunatic or a liar. It would be foolish to trust Jesus to save you or to follow him if he is not Lord of all as he claimed. If I say, “Jesus is Lord,” that means he is my master in every area of my life. This declaration is more than intellectual assent or lip service. It means we submit ourselves fully to him.
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_3_part_1">
        ## Lordship demands Obedience\n\n

        2. From Luke 6:46 and Matthew 7:21, what did Jesus teach us about Lordship?\n\n
        *“Why do you call me Lord, Lord, and do not do what I tell you?” (Luke 6:46)*\n\n
        *“Not everyone who says to me, Lord, Lord, will enter the Kingdom of heaven, but **the one who does the will** of my father who is in heaven.” (Matthew 7:21)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_3_part_2">
        As disciples of Jesus, our lives must be characterized by growing obedience to his commands.\n\n

        3. According to Jesus what is the Great Commandment in the Bible we must obey?\n\n
        *“Teacher, which is the great commandment in the Law?” And he said to him, “**You shall love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind**. This is the great and first commandment. And a second is like it: **You shall love your neighbor as yourself**. On these two commandments depend all the Law and the Prophets.” (Matthew 22:36-40)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_3_part_3">
        4. According to John 14:15, what does real love for God look like?\n\n
        *“If you love me, you will **keep my commandments**. (John 14:15)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_4_part_1">
        5. What is God’s view of the person who goes through life pursuing wealth?\n\n
        *And he told them a parable, saying, “The land of a rich man produced plentifully, and he thought to himself, ‘What shall I do, for I have nowhere to store my crops?’ And he said, ‘I will do this: I will tear down my barns and build larger ones, and there I will store all my grain and my goods. And I will say to my soul, “Soul, you have ample goods laid up for many years; relax, eat, drink, be merry.”’ But God said to him, ‘Fool! This night your soul is required of you, and the things you have prepared, whose will they be?’ So is the one who lays up treasure for himself and is not rich toward God.” (Luke 12:16-21)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_4_part_2">
        There’s nothing wrong with wealth. What is wrong is when money and possession replace the role of God in our life. Jesus calls a person who trusts and pursues wealth more than the will of God a fool.\n\n

        6. Is it possible to serve God and the world or ourselves?\n\n
        *“**No one can serve two masters**, for either he will hate the one and love the other, or he will be devoted to the one and despise the other. **You cannot serve God and money**. (Matthew 6:24)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_5_part_1">
        7. Where should we store our treasure?\n\n
        *“Do not lay up for yourselves treasures on earth, where moth and rust destroy and where thieves break in and steal, but *lay up for yourselves treasures in heaven*, where neither moth nor rust destroys and where thieves do not break in and steal. For where your treasure is, there your heart will be also. (Matthew 6:19-21)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_5_part_2">
        8. What is the major difference between the things of the world and the things of God?\n\n
        *Do not love the world or the things in the world. If anyone loves the world, the love of the Father is not in him. For all that is in the world——the desires of the flesh and the desires of the eyes and pride of life——**is not from the Father** but is from the world. And **the world is passing away along with its desires**, but whoever does the will of God abides forever. (1 John 2:15-17)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_6_part_1">
        ## Lordship begins in the heart\n\n

        9. According to 1 Peter 3:5, where does honoring Christ as Lord begins?\n\n
        *“But *in your hearts* honor Christ the Lord as holy” (I Peter 3:5)*\n\n

        Submitting to Christ as Lord is not about following a set of religious rules and traditions. Rather, **lordship is a matter of the heart**. Lordship begins as an internal submission of the heart. If it is genuine, it will eventually manifest itself in obedience.\n\n

        10. Explain in your own words what Colossians 3:23-24 means:\n\n
        *Whatever you do, work heartily, as for the Lord and not for men, knowing that from the Lord you will receive the inheritance as your reward. You are serving the Lord Christ. (Colossians 3:23-24)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_6_part_2">
        ## Lordship is a Continuous Walk\n\n

        11. What is the evidence that Jesus is your Lord?\n\n
        *“Therefore, as you received Christ Jesus the Lord so walk in him” (Colossians 2:6)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_6_part_3">
        We begin our Christian walk by acknowledging that Jesus is Lord. We must continue to walk under his lordship for the rest of our lives. Lordship is not having a one-time experience with God, but developing a lifetime walk with God. The more we know Him, the more we submit to Him.\n\n

        12. What does Luke 9:23 says we must continually do as we walk under the Lordship of Christ day by day?\n\n
        *And he said to all, “If anyone would come after me, **let him deny himself and take up his cross daily** and follow me. (Luke 9:23)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_7_part_1">
        Following Jesus and making him Lord means denying myself daily. It means that when what I want conflicts with what God wants, I have denied what I want to do what God wants.\n\n

        What do you think this means practically in your life?
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_7_part_2">
        13. What promise do we have from God if we are willing to put Him first?\n\n
        *But seek first the kingdom of God and his righteousness, and **all these things will be added to you**. (Matthew 6:33)*\n\n
        *And **my God will supply every need** of yours according to his riches in glory in Christ Jesus. (Philippians 4:19)*
    </string>
    <string name="lordship_page_7_part_3">
        ## Personal Application\n\n

        * Are there areas in your life that you have not yet submitted to the Lordship of Jesus Christ? Areas you are struggling to obey God.\n
        * Are your relationships under his lordship?\n
        * Are your finances under his lordship?\n
        * Is your time submitted to his lordship?\n

        ## MEMORY VERSE\n\n

        *…if you confess with your mouth that Jesus is Lord and believe in your heart that God raised him from the dead, you will be saved. (Romans 10:9)*
    </string>

    <!-- identity strings -->
    <string name="identity_page_1_part_1">
        ## CONNECT\n\n

        * How would your friends describe you? What would they say are your strengths, gifts, and weaknesses?\n
        * What would you like to do when you get some free time (e.g., hobby or collection)?\n\n

        ## STUDY\n\n

        *Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, **who has blessed us in Christ** with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places… (Ephesians 1:3)*\n\n

        Becoming a Christian means being a new creation. But what does it mean? It means that you have a **new identity**.\n\n

        Who am I? How do I see myself? How does God see me? What does God think of me? These are questions of identity that requires thoughtful study. How you see yourself impacts all the areas of your life, including your work and career, who you will marry, how you relate to others, and how you respond to life’s situations. It impacts the way you live the Christian life.\n\n

        Consider the list below and check three of the lines that best apply to you.
    </string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_1">what others think of me</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_2">my weaknesses</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_3">my grade point average</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_4">my physical strengths</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_5">what I look in the mirror</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_6">the friends I hang out with</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_7">my talents and abilities</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_8">my intelligence</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_9">what my family says about me</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_10">my family’s reputation</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_11">my attitude</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_12">what God says about me</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_13">the clothes I wear</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_14">Others.</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_part_2">
        There are many books written on the topic of self-esteem and identity. But only one book remains the same over time and is true for all situations and all people.
        This book is the Bible. Through it, God gives us His perspective on who we are and our relationship to Him. It lays a true foundation for self-identity.\n\n

        Who are you as a Christian?
    </string>
    <string name="identity_page_2_part_1">
        ## You Are a Saint with A New Position\n\n

        1. How did Paul address the Christians in Corinth? (1 Corinthians 1:2)\n\n
        *To the church of God that is in Corinth, to those **sanctified** in Christ Jesus, **called to be saints**… (1 Corinthians 1:2)*
    </string>
    <string name="identity_page_2_part_2">
        The word ‘saint’ means ‘holy ones’ or ‘righteous ones’ and it is a term used to describe all true believers. If you are a believer, you are a saint.\n\n
        2. As a saint how does God see you in Romans 3:24?\n\n
        *“Being **justified** freely by His grace through the redemption that is in Christ Jesus” (Romans 3:24)*
    </string>
    <string name="identity_page_2_part_3">
        What does being *justified* means?\n\n

        The word ‘justified’ means ‘to be declared righteous.’ It means God no longer sees you as a sinner; it means that God has **no record** that you have ever sinned. It also means that **you are righteous** in your standing before God. It is as if you have obeyed and fulfilled every command of God in the Scripture.\n\n

        3. As a saint in Romans 6:6, what has God freed you from?\n\n

        *“Knowing this, that our old man was crucified with Him, that the body of sin might be done away with, that we **should no longer be slaves of sin**” (Romans 6:6)*
    </string>
    <string name="identity_page_2_part_4">
        At that very moment of our salvation sin lost its power and its control in your life and you were set free from the slavery of sin.
    </string>
    <string name="identity_page_3_part_1">
        4. What does it mean that God has freed you from the power of sin?\n\n

        ***Let not sin therefore reign** in your mortal body, **to make you obey its passions**. **Do not present your members** to sin as instruments for unrighteousness, but **present yourselves to God** as those who have been brought from death to life, and your members to God as instruments for righteousness. **For sin will have no dominion over you**, since you are not under law but under grace. (Romans 6:12-14)*
    </string>
    <string name="identity_page_3_part_2">
        When you trusted Christ as Savior at that moment **sin lost its ownership**, its **control**, and all **authority in your life**. We are now free to say ‘**no**’ to sin and to say ‘**yes**’ to God. We are free from the power of greed, pride, envy, and covetousness. We are free from unsatisfied desires and frustrated passions. We are free from our insecurities and our fear of failure. **We do not have to be dominated** by the lust of the flesh or controlled
by the ways of the world. We are now free to begin living as a saint with a new position.\n\n

        ## You Are a Son with A New Power\n\n

        *“Therefore, you are no longer a slave **but a son and if a son, then an heir of God through Christ**” (Galatians 4:7)*\n\n

        The very moment you trusted Christ as Savior, the heavenly father accepted you as a son, making you a member of His family.
    </string>
    <string name="identity_page_4_part_1">
        5. What did Paul says we become part of when we trust in Jesus?\n\n

        *“You are no longer strangers and foreigners, but fellow citizens with the saints and **members of the household of God**” (Ephesians 2:19)*
    </string>
    <string name="identity_page_4_part_2">
        And as members of God’s family, you have received all the rights and privileges of a family member.\n\n

        6. In Galatians 4:6, what did our heavenly father give to us?\n\n

        *“And because you are sons, God has sent **forth the Spirit of His Son** into your hearts” (Galatians 4:6)*
    </string>
    <string name="identity_page_4_part_3">
        7. Why did the Father give us the Holy Spirit?\n\n

        *For if you live according to the flesh you will die, but **if by the Spirit you put to death** the deeds of the body, you will live. (Romans 8:13)*\n\n

        ***Mortify (put to death)** your members which are on the earth: fornication, uncleanness, passion, evil desires, and covetousness which is idolatry” (Colossians 3:5)*\n\n

        God has given us the power through the indwelling Spirit to do what we cannot do and that is to **put to death our flesh**. God never reveals a sin to confess, a lifestyle to forsake, a promise to claim, or a command to obey **without giving us the power to do it**. The power to do what God asks us to do is through the power of the Holy Spirit.
    </string>
    <string name="identity_page_5_part_1">
        8. As a son, what is our greatest privilege?\n\n

        *And because you are sons, God has sent forth the Spirit of His Son into your hearts, **crying Abba, Father**” (Galatians 4:6)*
    </string>
    <string name="identity_page_5_part_2">
        One of the greatest privileges of being a child of God is that we have unlimited access to the throne of God and whether it be day or night, anytime and anywhere God hears our every prayer.\n\n

        ## You Are a Servant with A New Purpose\n\n

        *“For we are His workmanship, created in Christ Jesus **unto good works**, which God had before ordained that we should walk in them” (Ephesians 2:10)*\n\n

        When you trusted Christ as your savior you became a new person and as a new person, you received a new position and a new power that you might fulfill a **new purpose**.\n\n

        9. According to Ephesians 2:10, what is our new purpose?\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="identity_page_5_part_3">
        10. According to Hebrews 10:24 and Matthew 5:14, how do we serve the lord?\n\n

        *"And let us consider how to **stir up one another to love and good works**” (Hebrews 10:24)*
    </string>
    <string name="identity_page_5_part_4">
        It is only when we understand who we are in Christ, will we begin to live supernaturally in Christ. It is when we see our- selves as a saint with a new position, a son with new power, and a servant with a new purpose will we begin to live up to our God-given potential in Christ.\n\n

        ## Personal Application\n\n

        * Are you living as a new creation in Christ Jesus?\n
        * Are there some changes you need to make to be fulfilling your God-given purpose in life?\n
        * How are you encouraging Christians for being a light to the lost?\n\n

        ## MEMORY VERSE\n\n

        *“You are the light of the world. A city set on a hill cannot be hidden." (Matthew 5:14)*
    </string>
    <string name="power_page_1">
        ## CONNECT\n\n

        * How would you describe your current experience as a Christian? (Growing, Frustrated, Disappointing, Fulfilled, Freeing, Stuck, Struggling, Joyful, Defeated, Exciting, Up and Down)\n\n

        ## STUDY\n\n

        *And while staying with them he ordered them not to depart from Jerusalem, but to wait for the promise of the father, which he said, you heard from me, for John baptized with water but you will be baptized with the Holy Spirit not many days from now… but you will receive power when the Holy Spirit has come upon you, and you will be my witnesses in Jerusalem and all Judea and Samaria, and the ends of the earth.” (Acts 1:4, 5, 8)*\n\n

        Before Jesus ascended into heaven, he told his disciples to wait for God’s promised gift, the Holy Spirit. A few days later, during the feast of Pentecost, God’s Spirit came in power and transformed the disciples into bold witnesses for Christ. As a result of the coming of the Holy Spirit, the believers began to courageously proclaim Jesus’ death and resurrection, the crowd responded in faith, and the New Testament church was birthed. (See Acts 1 &amp; 2)
    </string>
    <string name="power_page_2_part_1">
        ## The Role of the Holy Spirit\n\n

        Jesus asked the disciples to wait until they received the gift of the Holy Spirit because he knew that it is impossible to live the Christian life apart from the power and presence of the Holy Spirit.\n\n

        1. In Romans 8:9, what did the Holy Spirit does in the believer which signifies that he belongs to Christ?\n\n

        *“ You, however, are not in the flesh but in the Spirit, if in **fact the Spirit of God dwells in you**. Anyone who does not have the Spirit of Christ does not belong to him.” (Romans 8:9)*
    </string>
    <string name="power_page_2_part_2">
        Every believer is indwelt by the Spirit of God.\n\n

        2. According to Romans8:16, what does the Holy Spirit do in our spirit?\n\n

        *"The Spirit himself **bears witness** with our spirit that we are children of God… (Romans 8:16)"*
    </string>
    <string name="power_page_2_part_3">
        To bear witness means to confirm that we are children of God.\n\n

        3. According to Romans 8:14, how do we know that we are children of God?\n\n
        *"For all who are **led by the Spirit** of God are sons of God. (Romans 8:14)"*
    </string>
    <string name="power_page_3_part_1">
        4. What is the ministry of the Spirit for us according to John 14:26?\n\n

        *But the helper, the Holy Spirit, whom the Father will send in my name, will **teach you all things** and **bring to your remembrance** all that I had said to you.” (John 14:26)*
    </string>
    <string name="power_page_3_part_2">
        One of the Spirit’s ministries is to remind us of God’s word. Every time we read our Bible; we must ask Him for His illumination to understand the Word of God.\n\n

        5. In Acts 1:8, what does the Spirit empower us for?\n\n

        *“But you will receive power when the Holy Spirit has come upon you. And **you will be my witnesses** in Jerusalem and in all Judea and Samaria, and to the end of the earth.” (Acts 1:8)*
    </string>
    <string name="power_page_3_part_3">
        The Holy Spirit empowers us to be effective witnesses of the Gospel.\n\n

        6. What does the Holy Spirit do with our weakness?\n\n

        *“Likewise, **the spirit helps us in our weaknesses**. For we do not know what to pray for as we ought, but the spirit himself intercedes for us with groanings too deep for words. And he who searches hearts knows what the mind of the spirit is, because the spirit intercedes for the Saints according to the will of God.” (Romans 8:26-27)*
    </string>
    <string name="power_page_3_part_4">
        The Holy Spirit helps us in our weaknesses. Especially in prayer because we don’t usually know what to pray for.\n\n

        7. According to Galatians 5:22-23, what does the Holy Spirit develop in us?\n\n

        *“But the **fruit** of the spirit is **love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faithfulness, gentleness, self-control**.” (Galatians 5:22-23)*
    </string>
    <string name="power_page_3_part_5">
        The Holy Spirit develops Christ-like character in us as we sub- mit to his influence and leadership in our life.
    </string>
    <string name="power_page_4_part_1">
        ## The Filling of the Holy Spirit\n\n

        Although every believer is indwelt with the Spirit not every believer is empowered by that indwelling Spirit. To be empowered with the Holy Spirit you must **be filled with the Spirit**.\n\n

        8. From these two verses, how can we be filled with the Holy Spirit?\n\n

        *“My grace is sufficient for you, **for my power is made perfect in weakness**.” Therefore, I will boast all the more gladly of my weaknesses, so that the power of Christ may rest upon me. For the sake of Christ, then, I am content with **weaknesses**, insults, hardships, persecutions, and calamities. For when I am **weak**, then I am strong.” (2 Corinthians 12:9-10)*\n\n

        *“If you then, who are evil, know how to give good gifts to your children, how much more will the heavenly Father give the Holy Spirit **to those who ask him!**” (Luke 11:13)*
    </string>
    <string name="power_page_4_part_2">
        To be filled with the Holy Spirit we need to come to a point where we acknowledge our weakness. We need to be dependent on Him. And then we need to ask Him to fill us.\n\n

        If you have not already asked to be filled with the Holy Spirit, I urge you right now to pray in faith that God would fill you and empower you with the Holy Spirit.\n\n

        You can pray something like this:\n\n

        *“Lord, I thank you for the promise of the Spirit’s power and I believe Your power is available for me. I believe You want to do powerful things in me and through me. So, fill me and empower me with Your Spirit that I might be used of you to turn this world to You, Amen.”*
    </string>
    <string name="power_page_5_part_1">
        ## The Spirit-filled Life\n\n

        9. From these verses what is the evidence of the Spirit-filled life?\n\n

        *“But I say, walk by the Spirit, and **you will not gratify the desires of the flesh**” (Galatians 5:16)*
    </string>
    <string name="power_page_5_part_2">
        *“But you will **receive power** when the Holy Spirit has come upon you, and **you will be my witnesses** in Jerusalem and in all Judea and Samaria, and to the end of the earth” (Acts 1:8)*
    </string>
    <string name="power_page_5_part_3">
        A Spirit-filled believer is empowered to overcome the flesh to live like Jesus and enabled to be a powerful witness to the world.\n\n

        ## Personal Application\n\n

        * How do you know that you are filled with the Holy Spirit?\n
        * What can you expect the Holy Spirit to do for you?\n
        * Are you daily acknowledging your weakness and asking to be filled by faith?\n

        ## MEMORY VERSE\n\n

        *"And do not get drunk with wine, for that is debauchery, but be filled with the Spirit" (Ephesians 5:18)*
    </string>
    <string name="devotion_page_1">
        ## CONNECT\n\n

        * Do you have a daily ritual to help you get your day started? What do you think are the benefits of having a daily morning ritual?\n\n

        ## STUDY\n\n

        *And they devoted themselves to the apostles teaching and the fellowship, to the breaking of bread and the prayers” (Acts 2:42)*\n\n

        What made the early church vibrant and healthy was their devotion to God. Because they were devoted to growing in their relationship with him, they developed disciplines that expressed this devotion. Two of these vital disciplines are reading the Bible and prayer.
    </string>
    <string name="devotion_page_2_part_1">
        ## The Word\n\n

        More than just a random collection of stories, poems, and letters, the Bible is the inspired written Word of God.\n\n

        1. What is Job’s attitude toward the Bible?\n\n

        *“I have not departed from the commandment of his lips, I have **treasured** the words of his mouth **more than my portion of food**” ( Job 23:12)*
    </string>
    <string name="devotion_page_2_part_2">
        2. What can we learn about the Bible in these verses?\n\n

        *"All Scripture is **breathed out by God** and profitable for teaching, for reproof, for correction, and for training in righteousness, that the man of God may be complete, equipped for every good work. (2 Timothy 3:16-17)"*\n\n

        *"…no prophecy of Scripture comes from someone’s own interpretation. For no prophecy was ever produced by the will of man, but men spoke from God as they were carried along by the Holy Spirit. (2 Peter 1:20-21)"*
    </string>
    <string name="devotion_page_2_part_3">
        Before turning to Christ, we lived by the world standards. Now we accept the Bible as the **final authority** for what we believe and how we live.\n\n

        God’s word is the ultimate and absolute standard for every area of life.\n\n

        The measure of our spiritual progress is not how much of the Bible we know, **but how much we obey**. Those who constantly learn but fail to obey end up deceiving themselves.\n\n

        3. If we only hear the Word and do not do what it says, what does it reveal about us?\n\n

        *“But be doers of the word, and **not hearers only, deceiving yourselves**” (James 1:22)*
    </string>
    <string name="devotion_page_2_part_4">
        If we are not practicing what the Bible says, then we are just deceiving ourselves. It is also how we resist temptation, how we become successful, and how we can know God’s will for our lives.
    </string>
    <string name="devotion_page_3_part_1">
        4. From these verses what can we do to ensure our spiritual growth?\n\n

        > *Like newborn infants, **long** for the pure spiritual milk, that by it you may grow up into salvation, if indeed you have tasted that the Lord is good (I Peter 2:2-3)*
    </string>
    <string name="devotion_page_3_part_2">
        > *How can a young man keep his way pure? By guarding it according to your word… **I have stored up your word in my heart**, that I might not sin against you (Psalm 11:9, 11)*
    </string>
    <string name="devotion_page_3_part_3">
        > *This book of the law shall not depart from your mouth, you shall **meditate on it day and night**, so that you may be careful **to do according to all that is written in it**. For then you will make your way prosperous, and then you will have good success (Joshua 1:8)*
    </string>
    <string name="devotion_page_3_part_4">
        > *Do not be conformed to this world, but **be transformed by the renewal of your mind**, that by testing you may discern what is the will of God, what is good and acceptable and perfect (Romans 12:2)*
    </string>
    <string name="devotion_page_4_part_1">
        ## Prayer\n\n

        Christianity is more than just a religion. It is first and foremost a relationship with God. The foundation of any healthy relationship is communication. The better the communication, the better the relationship will be. God talks to us in many ways but primarily through his word, the Bible. We talked to him through prayer. We learned to listen to the sound of God’s voice in our lives when we read his word. He listens to us when we pray. Respond to his word with action. He responds to our prayers with action.\n\n

        Jesus is our best example for prayer. By observing his personal prayer life, we can learn how to have an intimate time of connection with the father.

        > *Now Jesus was praying in a certain place, and when he finished, one of his disciples said to him, Lord teach us to pray, as John taught his disciples (Luke 11:1)*\n\n

        5. From Matthew 6:5,7,8, what is a hypocritical prayer?\n\n

        > *And when you pray, you must not be like the hypocrites. For they love to stand and pray in the synagogues and at the street corners, **that they may be seen by others**. Truly, I say to you, they have received their reward. And when you pray, **do not heap up empty phrases as the Gentiles do**, for they think that they will be heard for their many words. Do not be like them, for your father knows what you need before you ask him (Matthew 6:5,7,8)*
    </string>
    <string name="devotion_page_4_part_2">
        6. What principles of prayer can you extract from the verses below?\n\n

        > *But when you pray, **go into your room** and shut the door and pray to your father who is in secret. And your father who sees in secret will reward you (Matthew 6:6)*
    </string>
    <string name="devotion_page_4_part_3">
        > *For there is one God, and there is **one mediator** between God and man, the man Christ Jesus (I Timothy 2:5)*
    </string>
    <string name="devotion_page_4_part_4">
        > *Jesus said to him I am the way and the truth and the life. No one comes to the father **except through me** ( John 14:6)*
    </string>
    <string name="devotion_page_4_part_5">
        Jesus told us to pray to the Father, not to the mother, saints, or angels. We are to pray through Jesus because He is the only way to the Father.
    </string>
    <string name="devotion_page_5_part_1">
        7. In Matthew 6:9-13, what did Jesus tell us to pray for?\n\n

        > *Pray then like this, our father in heaven, hallowed be your name. **Your Kingdom come, your will be done**, on earth as it is in heaven. **Give us this day Our Daily Bread, and forgive us our debts**, as we also have forgiven our debtors. And **lead us not into temptation**, but deliver us from evil (Matthew 6:9-13)*
    </string>
    <string name="devotion_page_5_part_2">
        Jesus taught his disciples to pray for God’s will to be done, provision, forgiveness, victory over temptation, and protection from the devil’s schemes.\n\n

        As you read and obey the word, and as we pray and trust God with our lives, let us not forget that **God answers prayer**. The more specific the prayers, the more specific the answers will be. The secret is to pray according to his will. We know his will by knowing his word. Therefore, as we pray according to his word, we know he will answer period.\n\n

        8. What did 1 John 5:14-15 promise when we pray according to His will?\n\n

        > *And this is the confidence that we have toward him, that if we ask anything according to his will, **he hears us**. And if we know that he hears us in whatever we ask, **we know that we have the requests that we have asked of him** (I John 5:14-15)*
    </string>
    <string name="devotion_page_5_part_3">
        ## Personal Application\n\n

        * Do you have a set time and place for daily Bible reading and prayer?\n
        * Are you involved in a discipleship group?\n
        * Have you forgiven all who have sinned against you?\n
        * Being praying for your daily bread.\n\n

        ## MEMORY VERSE\n\n

        > *And they devoted themselves to the apostles’ teaching and the fellowship, to the breaking of bread and the prayers. (Acts 2:42)*
    </string>
</resources>
