<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="identity_page_1_part_1">
        ## CONNECT\n\n

        * How would your friends describe you? What would they say are your strengths, gifts, and weaknesses?\n
        * What would you like to do when you get some free time (e.g., hobby or collection)?\n\n

        ## STUDY\n\n

        > *Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, **who has blessed us in Christ** with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places… (Ephesians 1:3)*\n\n

        Becoming a Christian means being a new creation. But what does it mean? It means that you have a **new identity**.\n\n

        Who am I? How do I see myself? How does God see me? What does God think of me? These are questions of identity that requires thoughtful study. How you see yourself impacts all the areas of your life, including your work and career, who you will marry, how you relate to others, and how you respond to life’s situations. It impacts the way you live the Christian life.\n\n

        Consider the list below and check three of the lines that best apply to you.
    </string>

    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_1">what others think of me</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_2">my weaknesses</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_3">my grade point average</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_4">my physical strengths</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_5">what I look in the mirror</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_6">the friends I hang out with</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_7">my talents and abilities</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_8">my intelligence</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_9">what my family says about me</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_10">my family’s reputation</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_11">my attitude</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_12">what God says about me</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_13">the clothes I wear</string>
    <string name="identity_page_1_identity_option_14">Others.</string>

    <string name="identity_page_1_part_2">
        There are many books written on the topic of self-esteem and identity. But only one book remains the same over time and is true for all situations and all people.
        This book is the Bible. Through it, God gives us His perspective on who we are and our relationship to Him. It lays a true foundation for self-identity.\n\n

        Who are you as a Christian?
    </string>

    <string name="identity_page_2_part_1">
        ## You Are a Saint with A New Position\n\n

        1. How did Paul address the Christians in Corinth? (1 Corinthians 1:2)\n
        > *To the church of God that is in Corinth, to those **sanctified** in Christ Jesus, **called to be saints**… (1 Corinthians 1:2)*
    </string>

    <string name="identity_page_2_part_2">
        The word ‘saint’ means ‘holy ones’ or ‘righteous ones’ and it is a term used to describe all true believers. If you are a believer, you are a saint.\n\n

        2. As a saint how does God see you in Romans 3:24?\n
        > *Being **justified** freely by His grace through the redemption that is in Christ Jesus (Romans 3:24)*
    </string>

    <string name="identity_page_2_part_3">
        What does being *justified* means?\n\n

        The word ‘justified’ means ‘to be declared righteous.’ It means God no longer sees you as a sinner; it means that God has **no record** that you have ever sinned. It also means that **you are righteous** in your standing before God. It is as if you have obeyed and fulfilled every command of God in the Scripture.\n\n

        3. As a saint in Romans 6:6, what has God freed you from?\n
        > *Knowing this, that our old man was crucified with Him, that the body of sin might be done away with, that we **should no longer be slaves of sin** (Romans 6:6)*
    </string>

    <string name="identity_page_2_part_4">
        At that very moment of our salvation sin lost its power and its control in your life and you were set free from the slavery of sin.
    </string>

    <string name="identity_page_3_part_1">
        4. What does it mean that God has freed you from the power of sin?\n
        > ***Let not sin therefore reign** in your mortal body, **to make you obey its passions**. **Do not present your members** to sin as instruments for unrighteousness, but **present yourselves to God** as those who have been brought from death to life, and your members to God as instruments for righteousness. **For sin will have no dominion over you**, since you are not under law but under grace. (Romans 6:12-14)*
    </string>

    <string name="identity_page_3_part_2">
        When you trusted Christ as Savior at that moment **sin lost its ownership**, its **control**, and all **authority in your life**. We are now free to say ‘**no**’ to sin and to say ‘**yes**’ to God. We are free from the power of greed, pride, envy, and covetousness. We are free from unsatisfied desires and frustrated passions. We are free from our insecurities and our fear of failure. **We do not have to be dominated** by the lust of the flesh or controlled
by the ways of the world. We are now free to begin living as a saint with a new position.\n\n

        ## You Are a Son with A New Power\n\n

        > *Therefore, you are no longer a slave **but a son and if a son, then an heir of God through Christ** (Galatians 4:7)*\n\n

        The very moment you trusted Christ as Savior, the heavenly father accepted you as a son, making you a member of His family.
    </string>

    <string name="identity_page_4_part_1">
        5. What did Paul says we become part of when we trust in Jesus?\n
        > *You are no longer strangers and foreigners, but fellow citizens with the saints and **members of the household of God** (Ephesians 2:19)*
    </string>

    <string name="identity_page_4_part_2">
        And as members of God’s family, you have received all the rights and privileges of a family member.\n\n

        6. In Galatians 4:6, what did our heavenly father give to us?\n
        > *And because you are sons, God has sent **forth the Spirit of His Son** into your hearts (Galatians 4:6)*
    </string>

    <string name="identity_page_4_part_3">
        7. Why did the Father give us the Holy Spirit?\n
        > *For if you live according to the flesh you will die, but **if by the Spirit you put to death** the deeds of the body, you will live. (Romans 8:13)*\n\n

        > ***Mortify (put to death)** your members which are on the earth: fornication, uncleanness, passion, evil desires, and covetousness which is idolatry (Colossians 3:5)*\n\n

        God has given us the power through the indwelling Spirit to do what we cannot do and that is to **put to death our flesh**. God never reveals a sin to confess, a lifestyle to forsake, a promise to claim, or a command to obey **without giving us the power to do it**. The power to do what God asks us to do is through the power of the Holy Spirit.
    </string>

    <string name="identity_page_5_part_1">
        8. As a son, what is our greatest privilege?\n
        > *And because you are sons, God has sent forth the Spirit of His Son into your hearts, **crying Abba, Father** (Galatians 4:6)*
    </string>

    <string name="identity_page_5_part_2">
        One of the greatest privileges of being a child of God is that we have unlimited access to the throne of God and whether it be day or night, anytime and anywhere God hears our every prayer.\n\n

        ## You Are a Servant with A New Purpose\n\n

        > *For we are His workmanship, created in Christ Jesus **unto good works**, which God had before ordained that we should walk in them (Ephesians 2:10)*\n\n

        When you trusted Christ as your savior you became a new person and as a new person, you received a new position and a new power that you might fulfill a **new purpose**.\n\n

        9. According to Ephesians 2:10, what is our new purpose?
    </string>

    <string name="identity_page_5_part_3">
        10. According to Hebrews 10:24 and Matthew 5:14, how do we serve the lord?\n
        > *And let us consider how to **stir up one another to love and good works** (Hebrews 10:24)*
    </string>

    <string name="identity_page_5_part_4">
        It is only when we understand who we are in Christ, will we begin to live supernaturally in Christ. It is when we see ourselves as a saint with a new position, a son with new power, and a servant with a new purpose will we begin to live up to our God-given potential in Christ.\n\n

        ## Personal Application\n\n

        * Are you living as a new creation in Christ Jesus?\n
        * Are there some changes you need to make to be fulfilling your God-given purpose in life?\n
        * How are you encouraging Christians for being a light to the lost?\n\n

        ## MEMORY VERSE\n\n

        > *You are the light of the world. A city set on a hill cannot be hidden. (Matthew 5:14)*
    </string>
</resources>