<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="power_page_1">
        ## CONNECT\n\n

        * How would you describe your current experience as a Christian? (Growing, Frustrated, Disappointing, Fulfilled, Freeing, Stuck, Struggling, Joyful, Defeated, Exciting, Up and Down)\n\n

        ## STUDY\n\n

        > *And while staying with them he ordered them not to depart from Jerusalem, but to wait for the promise of the father, which he said, you heard from me, for John baptized with water but you will be baptized with the Holy Spirit not many days from now… but you will receive power when the Holy Spirit has come upon you, and you will be my witnesses in Jerusalem and all Judea and Samaria, and the ends of the earth. (Acts 1:4,5,8)*\n\n

        Before Jesus ascended into heaven, he told his disciples to wait for God’s promised gift, the Holy Spirit. A few days later, during the feast of Pentecost, God’s Spirit came in power and transformed the disciples into bold witnesses for Christ. As a result of the coming of the Holy Spirit, the believers began to courageously proclaim Jesus’ death and resurrection, the crowd responded in faith, and the New Testament church was birthed. (See Acts 1 &amp; 2)
    </string>

    <string name="power_page_2_part_1">
        ## The Role of the Holy Spirit\n\n

        Jesus asked the disciples to wait until they received the gift of the Holy Spirit because he knew that it is impossible to live the Christian life apart from the power and presence of the Holy Spirit.\n\n

        1. In Romans 8:9, what did the Holy Spirit does in the believer which signifies that he belongs to Christ?\n\n

        > *You, however, are not in the flesh but in the Spirit, if in **fact the Spirit of God dwells in you**. Anyone who does not have the Spirit of Christ does not belong to him. (Romans 8:9)*
    </string>

    <string name="power_page_2_part_2">
        Every believer is indwelt by the Spirit of God.\n\n

        2. According to Romans8:16, what does the Holy Spirit do in our spirit?\n
        > *The Spirit himself **bears witness** with our spirit that we are children of God… (Romans 8:16)*
    </string>

    <string name="power_page_2_part_3">
        To bear witness means to confirm that we are children of God.\n\n

        3. According to Romans 8:14, how do we know that we are children of God?\n
        > *For all who are **led by the Spirit** of God are sons of God. (Romans 8:14)*
    </string>

    <string name="power_page_3_part_1">
        4. What is the ministry of the Spirit for us according to John 14:26?\n
        > *But the Helper, the Holy Spirit, whom the Father will send in my name, will **teach you all things** and **bring to your remembrance** all that I had said to you. (John 14:26)*
    </string>

    <string name="power_page_3_part_2">
        One of the Spirit’s ministries is to remind us of God’s word. Every time we read our Bible; we must ask Him for His illumination to understand the Word of God.\n\n

        5. In Acts 1:8, what does the Spirit empower us for?\n
        > *But you will receive power when the Holy Spirit has come upon you. And **you will be my witnesses** in Jerusalem and in all Judea and Samaria, and to the end of the earth. (Acts 1:8)*
    </string>

    <string name="power_page_3_part_3">
        The Holy Spirit empowers us to be effective witnesses of the Gospel.\n\n

        6. What does the Holy Spirit do with our weakness?\n
        > *Likewise, **the spirit helps us in our weaknesses**. For we do not know what to pray for as we ought, but the spirit himself intercedes for us with groanings too deep for words. And he who searches hearts knows what the mind of the spirit is, because the spirit intercedes for the Saints according to the will of God. (Romans 8:26-27)*
    </string>

    <string name="power_page_3_part_4">
        The Holy Spirit helps us in our weaknesses. Especially in prayer because we don’t usually know what to pray for.\n\n

        7. According to Galatians 5:22-23, what does the Holy Spirit develop in us?\n
        > *But the **fruit** of the spirit is **love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faithfulness, gentleness, self-control**. (Galatians 5:22-23)*
    </string>

    <string name="power_page_3_part_5">
        The Holy Spirit develops Christ-like character in us as we sub- mit to his influence and leadership in our life.
    </string>

    <string name="power_page_4_part_1">
        ## The Filling of the Holy Spirit\n\n

        Although every believer is indwelt with the Spirit not every believer is empowered by that indwelling Spirit. To be empowered with the Holy Spirit you must **be filled with the Spirit**.\n\n

        8. From these two verses, how can we be filled with the Holy Spirit?\n
        > *\“My grace is sufficient for you, **for my power is made perfect in weakness**.\” Therefore, I will boast all the more gladly of my weaknesses, so that the power of Christ may rest upon me. For the sake of Christ, then, I am content with **weaknesses**, insults, hardships, persecutions, and calamities. For when I am **weak**, then I am strong. (2 Corinthians 12:9-10)*\n\n

        > *If you then, who are evil, know how to give good gifts to your children, how much more will the heavenly Father give the Holy Spirit **to those who ask him!** (Luke 11:13)*
    </string>

    <string name="power_page_4_part_2">
        To be filled with the Holy Spirit we need to come to a point where we acknowledge our weakness. We need to be dependent on Him. And then we need to ask Him to fill us.\n\n

        If you have not already asked to be filled with the Holy Spirit, I urge you right now to pray in faith that God would fill you and empower you with the Holy Spirit.\n\n

        You can pray something like this:\n\n

        *Lord, I thank you for the promise of the Spirit’s power and I believe Your power is available for me. I believe You want to do powerful things in me and through me. So, fill me and empower me with Your Spirit that I might be used of you to turn this world to You, Amen.*
    </string>

    <string name="power_page_5_part_1">
        ## The Spirit-filled Life\n\n

        9. From these verses what is the evidence of the Spirit-filled life?\n
        > *But I say, walk by the Spirit, and **you will not gratify the desires of the flesh** (Galatians 5:16)*
    </string>

    <string name="power_page_5_part_2">
        > *But you will **receive power** when the Holy Spirit has come upon you, and **you will be my witnesses** in Jerusalem and in all Judea and Samaria, and to the end of the earth (Acts 1:8)*
    </string>

    <string name="power_page_5_part_3">
        A Spirit-filled believer is empowered to overcome the flesh to live like Jesus and enabled to be a powerful witness to the world.\n\n

        ## Personal Application\n\n

        * How do you know that you are filled with the Holy Spirit?\n
        * What can you expect the Holy Spirit to do for you?\n
        * Are you daily acknowledging your weakness and asking to be filled by faith?\n\n

        ## MEMORY VERSE\n\n

        > *And do not get drunk with wine, for that is debauchery, but be filled with the Spirit (Ephesians 5:18)*
    </string>
</resources>