<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="salvation_page_1">
        ## CONNECT\n\n

        * What comes into your mind when you think of the word salvation?\n
        * In your own opinion, why do you think we need to be saved? Or do we need to be saved?\n\n

        ## STUDY\n\n

        > *Therefore, if anyone is **in Christ**, he is a **new creation**. The old has passed away; behold, **the new has come**. (2 Corinthians 5:17)*\n\n

        In its simplest sense, being a Christian means being a **new creation**. It means a fresh start. That’s good news for all of us. However, before we can appreciate the good news, we need to understand why we need to start over. Why do we need to become a new creation? Why do we need salvation?
    </string>

    <string name="salvation_page_2_part_1">
        ## The Problem\n\n

        1. There is an immeasurable gap separating God and man. What is the cause of this eternal separation? (Read Isaiah 59:1-2)\n
        > *Behold, the Lord’s hand is not shortened, that it cannot save, or his ear dull, that it cannot hear; but your iniquities have made a separation between you and your God, and your sins have hidden his face from you so that he does not hear. (Isaiah 59:1-2)*
    </string>

    <string name="salvation_page_2_part_2">
        Have you ever felt distant from God? We all have. Feeling far from God is very common. Many who sense the vast separation suppose that if they meditate harder, learn more about their religion, or just step into a religious sanctuary, they will be closer to God. But our separation from God is not just physical or intellectual so neither meditation nor knowledge or religious ritual can bring us any closer to God.\n\n

        2. How does the Bible describe this separation?\n
        > *…for all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God… (Romans 3:23)*
    </string>

    <string name="salvation_page_3_part_1">
        The separation between God and man is **moral separation**. God is holy, man is not. God is good, man is not. God\'s standard is his glory, meaning his perfections. The problem is that we cannot be morally perfect like God. That’s why all are **eternally separated** from God. In other words, we are **disqualified** on our own to go to heaven.\n\n

        3. Furthermore, we need to understand that **sin has consequences**. What is the eternal consequence of our sin according to Romans 6:23?\n
        > *For the wages of sin is **death**… (Romans 6:23)*
    </string>

    <string name="salvation_page_3_part_2">
        The consequence of our sin is eternal death. Eternal separation from God in a place called Hell.\n\n

        ## The Solution\n\n

        The Good News is that God did not leave us on our own to deal with our sins. God’s justice demands that **sin must be punished**. That’s why Jesus came to sacrifice Himself and paid the penalty for our sin on the cross.\n\n

        **God is holy**, righteous, and just, that’s why he could not allow sin to go unpunished. But **God is loving** and compassionate and merciful, he did not want man to be eternally separated from him. How can God punish our sins without eternally condemning us from His presence?\n\n

        The divine solution to this problem was for Jesus, God’s only son, to become the sacrifice for our sin.
    </string>

    <string name="salvation_page_4_part_1">
        4. How did Jesus’ deal with our sin according to Hebrews 9:26-28?\n
        > *…for then he would have had to suffer repeatedly since the foundation of the world. But as it is, he has **appeared once** for all at the end of the ages **to put away sin by the sacrifice of himself**. And just as it is appointed for man to die once, and after that comes judgment, so Christ, **having been offered once to bear the sins of many**, will appear a second time, not to deal with sin but to save those who are eagerly waiting for him. (Hebrews 9:26-28)*
    </string>

    <string name="salvation_page_4_part_2">
        What exactly happened on the cross? Through his death on the cross, **Jesus took our place and our punishment**. He **exchanged** his righteousness for our sin. He took our curse and gave us His blessing. Because of his sinless life, Jesus was the only one qualified to pay the penalty for man’s sin and to bridge the gap between God and man.\n\n

        5. What did God do for us in Jesus according to 2 Corinthians 5:21?\n
        > *For our sake he made him **to be sin** who knew no sin, so that in him **we might become the righteousness of God**. (2 Corinthians 5:21)
    </string>

    <string name="salvation_page_5_part_1">
        6. What did Christ redeem us **from** in Galatians 3:13?\n
        > *Christ redeemed us **from the curse of the law** by becoming a curse for us——for it is written, “Cursed is everyone who is hanged on a tree” (Galatians 3:13)*
    </string>

    <string name="salvation_page_5_part_2">
        ## The Result\n\n

        Christ died on the cross so that we might receive **forgiveness** of our sins, be **reconciled** to God, have **eternal life**, and **be indwelt by the Spirit**.\n\n

        *Forgiveness*\n\n

        7. In Ephesians 1:7, what did we receive in Jesus?\n
        > *In Him, we have **redemption** through His blood, the **forgiveness of our trespasses**, according to the riches of His grace… (Ephesians 1:7)*
    </string>

    <string name="salvation_page_5_part_3">
        8. How many sins did God forgive us in Jesus? (1 John 1:7)\n
        > *…the blood of Jesus his Son cleanses us from all sin. (1 John 1:7)*\n\n

        God forgives us and cleanses us from all of our sins. All means our past, present, and future sins. Our status before God in Christ is forgiven.
    </string>

    <string name="salvation_page_6_part_1">
        *Reconciliation*\n\n

        Our sins make us the enemy of God. But the good news of the Gospel is that God in Christ offers us reconciliation to God.\n\n

        9. What did Romans 5:10 say about our past and present status before God?\n
        > *For if while we were **enemies** we were **reconciled** to God by the death of His Son, much more, now that we are reconciled, shall we be saved by His life. (Romans 5:10)*
    </string>

    <string name="salvation_page_6_part_2">
        To be reconciled with God means God is no longer your enemy. You have been brought near to God through Jesus as a friend.\n\n

        *Eternal Life*\n\n

        Not only does God forgives us and reconciles us through Jesus, but He also gives us eternal life.\n\n
        > *“For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have *eternal life*. (John 3:16)*\n\n

        10. What is eternal life according to John 17:3?\n
        > *And this is eternal life, that **they know you the only true God**, and Jesus Christ whom you have sent. (John 17:3)*
    </string>

    <string name="salvation_page_7">
        Eternal life does not primarily refer to quantity but the quality of life. It is a life of knowing God and Jesus. It is a life lived with God.\n\n

        *Indwelt by the Spirit*\n\n

        One of the blessings of being a Christian is to be indwelt by God’s Spirit.\n\n

        > *If the Spirit of him who raised Jesus from the dead dwells in you, he who raised Christ Jesus from the dead will also give life to your mortal bodies through his Spirit who dwells in you. (Romans 8:11)*\n\n

        When you accept Christ as your Savior, the Holy Spirit takes up **residence** in your heart, bringing with Him an entirely new life of love, relationship, and service to the Lord.\n\n

        This is what it means to be a new creation.To have a fresh start.\n\n

        ## The Response\n\n

        How do we receive this salvation? We receive salvation when we **stop trusting in ourselves** and **start trusting in who Christ is and what He has done for us**.
        Our salvation is the result of **God’s grace**. It is based on what Jesus did for us on the cross. It has nothing to do with what we do for him. We cannot save ourselves or earn God’s approval through the good works we do.\n\n

        11. Can we earn our salvation through good works? Read Ephesians 2:8-9.\n
        > *For by grace, you have been saved through faith. And **this is not your own doing; it is the gift of God**, not a result of works, so that no one may boast. (Ephesians 2:8-9)*
    </string>

    <string name="salvation_page_8_part_1">
        12. According to the verse above, how do you receive this gift?
    </string>

    <string name="salvation_page_8_part_2">
        What is saving faith?\n\n

        * Saving faith means you **understand intellectually**. You need to know that you are a sinner and therefore unworthy to go to heaven. You also need to understand the purpose and the reason why Jesus died on the cross for you.\n
        * Saving faith means you **agree emotionally**. Not only do you understand it, but you heartily agree with it. You are struck emotionally by how much God loves you on the cross of Jesus Christ.\n
        * Saving faith means you **trust volitionally**. It means you totally depend on Jesus’ work on the cross alone for your salvation.\n\n

        13. What does it look like to express this kind of saving faith? (Read Romans 10:9-10)\n
        > *…if you **confess** with your mouth that Jesus is Lord and **believe in your heart** that God raised him from the dead, you will be saved. (Romans 10:9)*
    </string>

    <string name="salvation_page_9">
        ## PERSONAL APPLICATION\n\n

        * Have you stopped trusting in yourself and started trusting in Christ alone for salvation?\n
        * Have you turned away from all known sin?\n
        * Have you confessed Jesus as the Lord and Master of your life?\n
        * Are you willing to follow and obey Him for the rest of your life?\n\n

        ## PRAY\n\n

        ### Prayer for Salvation\n\n

        Heavenly Father, I acknowledged the separation between us… It is because of my sins. I confess that I have sinned and have fallen short of your glory. Thank you that you sent your Son, Jesus to pay the penalty for my sin. I believe that He died on the cross for me. I believe that you raised him from the dead. I am sorry for my sins, and I ask you to forgive and cleanse me.
        I want to turn away from everything the Bible calls sin and receive Jesus as my Lord, Master, and Savior. Help me to love, serve and obey you for the rest of my life in Jesus’ name, Amen.
    </string>

    <string name="salvation_page_10">
        ## A New Life\n\n

        If you have sincerely prayed that prayer, the Bible promises that the old has passed away and new has come. The next lessons will introduce you to some of the new things that have come.\n\n

        ## MEMORY VERSE\n\n

        > *For by grace you have been saved through faith. And this is not your own doing; it is the gift of God, not a result of works, so that no one may boast. (Ephesians 2:8-9)*
    </string>
</resources>